GIAN KARLA BANARES

gbcodedev@gmail.com | (650) 796-7589 | http://gbcodedev.com

SUMMARY

Creative Software Engineer with a complete understanding of the development lifecycle. Track record of building visibility, recognition and positive market presence for diverse products and services. A creative problem-solver with the proven ability to manage projects from ideation to application launch. Expert experience gained from project management, data and business analysis, and UI/UX design.

SKILLS

MySQL, Mongo, Express, Ajax, JavaScript, NodeJS, NextJS, Firebase, Gatsby, React, Git, Adobe CS Photoshop, Illustrator,

InDesign, Wordpress, Project Management, Graphic Design, UX/UI, Usability Testing, Information Architecture, Team Management, Style Guides, User Flow Design, Data Modeling, Product Strategy, Content Creation, Marketing

PROJECTS

Piggy Business | http://piggy.business

Lead Software Engineer

• Technologies: React, MySQL, Handlebars, Materialize CSS, JavaScript, ExpressJS, NodeJS, Figma, Sketch

Fruit Spotter | http://fruitspotter.com

Lead Software Engineer

• Technologies: Firebase, MySQL, Google Maps, Figma, Sketch, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, NodeJS

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer (Freelance) - San Jose, CA - January 2019 to Present

Delivering applications for clients from ideation to final delivery. Liaise between development team and business owners, as well as creating documentation, functional specifications and communicating project status and updates.

Visual/Graphic Designer (Freelance) - San Jose, CA - February 2015 to Present

Brand Management/Development for clients; review, write and edit content for internal/external communications. Create presentations, data analysis, budgets and manage reporting requirements.

Creative Design Analyst - ALOM Technologies - Fremont, CA - January 2012 to January 2015 Collaborated with Business Owners and Developers to create and maintain a brand management portal. Created UX/UI for B2B/B2C sites along with technical training content for manual and video guides. Managed e-commerce websites and content for various business clients.

Web & Graphic Designer - ALOM Technologies - Fremont, CA - April 2009 to December 2011 Supported the Sales & Marketing teams with graphics support for presentations. Created and maintained Branding Guidelines. Graphics Design for print and web. Video production for marketing and IT projects.

EDUCATION

Coding Bootcamp, Full Stack - UC Berkeley Extension, Berkeley, CA Chemical Engineering Technology - Seneca College, Toronto, Canada